{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Network Technology",
    "Term": "Finals",
    "Title": "06 Static and Dynamic Routing",
    "LastModified": "15 June 2024",
    "Authors": [
      ""
    ],
    "References": [
      "05 Handout 1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData":[
    {
      "question": "These routes are manually configured by network administrators, have low system requirements, and apply to simple, stable, and small networks",
      "answer": "Static routes",
      "choices": [
        "Static routes",
        "Dynamic Routes",
        "Default Routes",
        "Open Shortest Path First"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The disadvantage of these routes is that they cannot automatically adapt to network topology changes and so require manual intervention",
      "answer": "Static routes",
      "choices": [
        "Static routes",
        "Dynamic Routes",
        "Routing Infomation Protocol",
        "Open Shortest Path First"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A static route needs to be manually configured so that the packets sent can be forwarded to the next hop.",
      "answer": "The statement is TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "The statement is TRUE .",
        "The statement is FALSE .",
        "Pero bakit parang kasalanan ko?",
        "Pass. Di to kasama sa nireview ko."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Specify a next-hop IP address for a static route",
      "answer": "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address",
      "choices": [
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address",
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number",
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number [",
        "[Huawei] ip route ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Specify an outbound interface for a static route.",
      "answer": "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number",
      "choices": [
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address",
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number",
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number [",
        "[Huawei] ip route ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Specify both the outbound interface and next hop for a static route.",
      "answer": "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number [",
      "choices": [
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address",
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number",
        "[Huawei] ip route-static ip-address { mask /mask-length } interface-type interface-number [",
        "[Huawei] ip route ip-address { mask /mask-length } nexthop-address"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Packets are forwarded to neighbor routers at once.",
      "answer": "The statement is FALSE . -- Packets are forwarded hop by hop",
      "choices": [
        "The statement is TRUE .",
        "The statement is FALSE . -- Packets are forwarded hop by hop",
        "The statement is FALSE . -- Packets cannot be forwarded.",
        "Pass. Wala to sa farm."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are used only when packets to be forwarded do not match any routing entry in an IP routing table?",
      "answer": "Default Routes",
      "choices": [
        "Static routes",
        "Dynamic Routes",
        "Default Routes",
        "Open Shortest Path First"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which statement is correct about default routes?",
      "answer": "A packet that matches no routing entry other than the default route is forwarded to an address mapped to the default route.",
      "choices": [
        "A packet that matches no routing entry other than the default route cannot be forwarded to an address mapped.",
        "A packet that matches no routing entry other than the default route is forwarded to an address mapped to the default route.",
        "A packet that matches no routing entry other than the default route is forwarded to an address mapped to the static route.",
        "A packet that matches no routing entry other than the default route is forwarded to an address mapped to the nearest route."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "If no default route is available, IP packets that do not match any routing entry will be silently discarded.",
      "answer": "The statement is TRUE .",
      "choices": [
        "The statement is TRUE .",
        "The statement is FALSE . -- IP packets that do not match any routing entry will be forwarded to static routes.",
        "The statement is FALSE . -- IP packets that do not match any routing entry will be forwarded to default routes.",
        "Pass. Di to kasama sa nireview ko."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Routers and computers always have a default route stored in their IP routing table.",
      "answer": "The statement is FALSE . -- Routers and computers may or may not have a default route stored in their IP routing table.",
      "choices": [
        "The statement is TRUE .",
        "The statement is FALSE . -- Routers and computers may or may not have a default route stored in their IP routing table.",
        "The statement is FALSE . -- Routers and computers need to configure the default route stored in their IP routing table before using.",
        "Pass. Wala to sa farm."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is true about static routes?",
      "answer": "To use these routes on any device, you must manually configure them.",
      "choices": [
        "To use these routes on any device, you must manually configure them.",
        "These routes can be automatically discovered and learned.",
        "Commonly used distance vector routing that uses its routing metric to determine the best route or shortest path.",
        "These routes are used only when packets to be forwarded do not match any routing entry in an IP routing table."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is true about static routes?",
      "answer": "These routes cannot adapt to link changes.",
      "choices": [
        "These routes cannot adapt to link changes.",
        "These routes can be automatically discovered and learned.",
        "These routes can adapt to topology changes.",
        "These routes are used only when packets to be forwarded do not match any routing entry in an IP routing table."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is true about dynamic routes?",
      "answer": "These routes can be automatically discovered and learned.",
      "choices": [
        "These routes can be automatically discovered and learned.",
        "These routes cannot adapt to link changes.",
        "To use these routes on any device, you must manually configure them.",
        "These routes are used only when packets to be forwarded do not match any routing entry in an IP routing table."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is true about dynamic routes?",
      "answer": "These routes can adapt to topology changes.",
      "choices": [
        "These routes can adapt to topology changes.",
        "These routes cannot adapt to link changes.",
        "To use these routes on any device, you must manually configure them.",
        "These routes are used only when packets to be forwarded do not match any routing entry in an IP routing table."
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a a collection of networks and subnetworks where routers need to exchange routing information in the interconnection of networks?",
      "answer": "Autonomous System",
      "choices": [
        "Autonomous System",
        "Default System",
        "Network Layer",
        "Network System"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the network that connects one AS to another within the AS?",
      "answer": "interior gateway",
      "choices": [
        "exterior gateway",
        "core network",
        "interior gateway",
        "autonomous system"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the network that connects all the autonomous systems together?",
      "answer": "core network",
      "choices": [
        "interior gateway",
        "exterior gateway",
        "core network",
        "autonomous system"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for the gateways that connect all the autonomous systems to the core network?",
      "answer": "exterior gateways",
      "choices": [
        "interior gateway",
        "core network",
        "exterior gateways",
        "autonomous system"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another term for core network?",
      "answer": "backbone",
      "choices": [
        "backbone",
        "t-bone",
        "bone marrow",
        "boneless"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the protocols classified as IGPs or EGPs used for in networking?",
      "answer": "Routing Protocols",
      "choices": [
        "Routing Protocols",
        "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
        "Border Gateway Protocol",
        "Routing algorithms"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What protocol is meant to dynamically route data across a network that you fully control and maintain?",
      "answer": "Interior Gateway Protocol",
      "choices": [
        "Interior Gateway Protocol",
        "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
        "Border Gateway Protocol",
        "Routing algorithms"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What protocol is used to exchange routes between distinctly separate networks that you have no administrative control over?",
      "answer": "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
      "choices": [
        "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
        "Interior Gateway Protocol",
        "Border Gateway Protocol",
        "Routing algorithms"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the routing protocol used on the Internet, commonly used to run on your internet edge when connecting to your ISP?",
      "answer": "Border Gateway Protocol",
      "choices": [
        "Border Gateway Protocol",
        "Interior Gateway Protocol",
        "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
        "Routing algorithms"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What determines good paths (routes) from senders to receivers through the network of routers?",
      "answer": "Routing algorithms",
      "choices": [
        "Routing algorithms",
        "Interior Gateway Protocol",
        "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
        "Border Gateway Protocol"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of path finds a path between the source and destination with the least cost?",
      "answer": "Least-cost path",
      "choices": [
        "Least-cost path",
        "Shortest path",
        "Default-cost path",
        "Long-cost path"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of path is the path with the smallest number of links between the source and the destination?",
      "answer": "Shortest path",
      "choices": [
        "Least-cost path",
        "Shortest path",
        "Default-cost path",
        "Long-cost path"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of routing protocol involves all routers sending their routing tables to only their neighboring routers?",
      "answer": "Distance-Vector Routing Protocol",
      "choices": [
        "Distance-Vector Routing Protocol",
        "Routing Information Protocol",
        "RIP Request",
        "RIP Response"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a commonly used distance vector routing protocol that uses its routing metric to determine the best route or shortest path a packet has to traverse from the source to a destination over a network?",
      "answer": "Routing Information Protocol",
      "choices": [
        "Routing Information Protocol",
        "Distance-Vector Routing Protocol",
        "RIP Request",
        "RIP Response"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to the number of routers through which a packet passes to reach its destination?",
      "answer": "hop count",
      "choices": [
        "hop count",
        "destination count",
        "router count",
        "router hop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the maximum number of hops designed for RIP?",
      "answer": "15 hops",
      "choices": [
        "15 hops",
        "10 hops",
        "25 hops",
        "30 hops"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "How often does a router running RIP send the contents of its routing table to each of its adjacent routers?",
      "answer": "30 seconds",
      "choices": [
        "30 seconds",
        "180 seconds",
        "15 seconds",
        "45 seconds"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "After how many seconds is a route flagged as unusable by the receiving routers when it is removed from the routing table in RIP?",
      "answer": "180 seconds",
      "choices": [
        "30 seconds",
        "180 seconds",
        "15 seconds",
        "45 seconds"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two types of RIP messages that routers exchange?",
      "answer": "request and response messages",
      "choices": [
        "request and response messages",
        "internal and external messages",
        "send and receive messages",
        "forward and backward messages"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of message does a RIP router send to all of its neighbors to request routing information of the entire RIP network when it starts up?",
      "answer": "RIP Request",
      "choices": [
        "RIP Request",
        "RIP Response",
        "RIP Protocol",
        "RIP Packet"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of message does a RIP router immediately reply with upon receipt of a RIP request?",
      "answer": "RIP Response",
      "choices": [
        "RIP Request",
        "RIP Response",
        "RIP Protocol",
        "RIP Packet"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What version of RIP uses IP broadcast packets for its announcements?",
      "answer": "RIPv1",
      "choices": [
        "RIPv1",
        "RIPv2",
        "RIPv3",
        "RIPv4"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What version of RIP allows IP multicast packets for its announcements?",
      "answer": "RIPv2",
      "choices": [
        "RIPv1",
        "RIPv2",
        "RIPv3",
        "RIPv4"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of routing protocol involves each of the routers sending the state of its own interfaces to all other routers only when there is a change to report?",
      "answer": "Link-state Routing Protocol",
      "choices": [
        "Link-state Routing Protocol",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "List of neighboring routers",
        "Link-State PDU"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to the description of the router interface in link-state routing protocol?",
      "answer": "Link-State (LS)",
      "choices": [
        "Output cost",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "Link-State Database (LSDB)",
        "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to the cost of sending data packets on the interface, expressed in the link state metric in link-state routing protocol?",
      "answer": "Output cost",
      "choices": [
        "Output cost",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "List of neighboring routers",
        "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to other routers that are attached through the link-state in link-state routing protocol?",
      "answer": "List of neighboring routers",
      "choices": [
        "Link-State Database (LSDB)",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "List of neighboring routers",
        "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to an OSPF data packet containing link-state and routing information that is shared with the other routers in link-state routing protocol?",
      "answer": "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)",
      "choices": [
        "Output cost",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "List of neighboring routers",
        "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to a unit of data describing the local state of router’s interfaces and adjacencies in link-state routing protocol?",
      "answer": "Link-State PDU",
      "choices": [
        "Link-State PDU",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "List of neighboring routers",
        "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term refers to a collection of all LS PDUs originated from the area’s routers in link-state routing protocol?",
      "answer": "Link-State Database (LSDB)",
      "choices": [
        "Link-State Database (LSDB)",
        "Link-State (LS)",
        "List of neighboring routers",
        "Link-State Advertisement (LSA)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process called when routers that run a link-state routing protocol establish a neighbor relationship and then exchange Link State Advertisements?",
      "answer": "LSA Flooding",
      "choices": [
        "LSA Flooding",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process of each router generating LSAs and adding the received LSAs to its own linkstate database (LSDB) called?",
      "answer": "LSDB Creation",
      "choices": [
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process of each router using the Shortest Path First (SPF) algorithm and LSDB information to calculate routes called?",
      "answer": "SPF Calculation",
      "choices": [
        "SPF Calculation",
        "LSDB Creation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process of the router installing routes for the calculated preferred paths into its routing table called?",
      "answer": "Routing Table Generation",
      "choices": [
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the link-state routing protocol developed by the IETF in 1988 that is capable of quickly detecting topological changes within the autonomous system and establishing loop-free routes in a short period of time, with minimum additional communication overhead for negotiating topology changes between peering routers?",
      "answer": "Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)",
      "choices": [
        "Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)",
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the OSPF area keyword that identifies an OSPF area called?",
      "answer": "Area",
      "choices": [
        "Area",
        "Router ID",
        "Cost Value",
        "Cost Hop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term uniquely identifies a router in an OSPF area?",
      "answer": "Router ID",
      "choices": [
        "Area",
        "Router ID",
        "Cost Value",
        "Cost Hop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What term does OSPF use as route metrics?",
      "answer": "Cost Value",
      "choices": [
        "Area",
        "Router ID",
        "Cost Value",
        "Cost Hop"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the important concepts about the relationship between OSPF routers?",
      "answer": "Neighbor relationship and adjacency",
      "choices": [
        "Neighbor relationship and adjacency",
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the special data packet (message) that is sent out periodically from a router to establish and confirm network adjacency relationships to other routers in the OSPF called?",
      "answer": "HELLO packet",
      "choices": [
        "HELLO packet",
        "HELLO WORLD packet",
        "TEST packet",
        "TEST NETWORK packet"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the first step in the Link-State Process?",
      "answer": "LSA Flooding",
      "choices": [
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "LSA Flooding"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the second step in the Link-State Process?",
      "answer": "LSDB Creation",
      "choices": [
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "LSA Flooding"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the third step in the Link-State Process?",
      "answer": "SPF Calculation",
      "choices": [
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "LSA Flooding"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the fourth step in the Link-State Process ?",
      "answer": "Routing Table Generation",
      "choices": [
        "LSDB Creation",
        "SPF Calculation",
        "Routing Table Generation",
        "LSA Flooding"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What command is used to display the OSPF neighbor table in Huawei routers?",
      "answer": "[R1] display ospf peer",
      "choices": [
        "[R1] display ospf peer",
        "[R1] display ospf routing",
        "[R1] display ospf ip address",
        "[R1] display ospf ip routing"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What command is used to display the OSPF routing table in Huawei routers?",
      "answer": "[R1] display ospf routing",
      "choices": [
        "[R1] display ospf routing",
        "[R1] display ospf peer",
        "[R1] display ospf ip peer",
        "[R1] display ospf ip routing peer"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the ISO name for a router in IS-IS terminologies?",
      "answer": "IS (Intermediate System)",
      "choices": [
        "IS (Intermediate System)",
        "NSAP (Network Service Access Point)",
        "CLNS (Connection-Less Network Service)",
        "IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What algorithm does IS-IS use to find the best path to each destination?",
      "answer": "Dijkstra’s (Shortest Path First) algorithm",
      "choices": [
        "Dijkstra’s (Shortest Path First) algorithm",
        "Floyd-Warshall algorithm",
        "Prim's algorithm",
        "Kruskal's algorithm"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the term for a device on the network, such as a server or workstation, in IS-IS terminologies?",
      "answer": "ES (End System)",
      "choices": [
        "ES (End System)",
        "NSAP (Network Service Access Point)",
        "CLNS (Connection-Less Network Service)",
        "IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the network service in the OSI stack in IS-IS terminologies?",
      "answer": "CLNS (Connection-Less Network Service)",
      "choices": [
        "CLNS (Connection-Less Network Service)",
        "ES (End System)",
        "NSAP (Network Service Access Point)",
        "IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a Layer-3 address for CLNS packets in IS-IS terminologies?",
      "answer": "NSAP (Network Service Access Point)",
      "choices": [
        "NSAP (Network Service Access Point)",
        "ES (End System)",
        "CLNS (Connection-Less Network Service)",
        "IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System)"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "What protocol forms neighbor adjacencies, has areas, exchanges link-state packets, builds a link-state database, and runs the Dijkstra’s algorithm to find the best path to each destination?",
      "answer": "IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System)",
      "choices": [
        "IS-IS (Intermediate System-to-Intermediate System)",
        "IS (Intermediate System)",
        "ES (End System)",
        "CLNS (Connection-Less Network Service)"
      ]
    }
  ]
}
